Ramon F. Adams papers, 1941-1969
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Ramon F. Adams papers, 1941-1969
AZ 310
Adams, Ramon F. (Ramon Frederick), 1889-1976
This collection includes correspondence and manuscripts chiefly concerning Western history and literature; it includes letters from friends, authors, editors, and publishers. Also included are original typescripts with holograph corrections of revised editions of his works Western Words: A Dictionary of the American West, 1968, and Six-Guns and Saddle Leather, 1969, both published by University of Oklahoma Press.
1.7 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Ramon F. Adams was a Western writer and bibliographer.
Organization
This collection is organized into two series:
Series I: Correspondence, 1946-1969
Series II: Manuscripts, 1941-1969
Scope and Content Note
This collection includes correspondence and manuscripts chiefly concerning Western history and literature; it includes letters from friends, authors, editors, and publishers. Also included are original typescripts with holograph corrections of revised editions of his works Western Words: A Dictionary of the American West, 1968, and Six-Guns and Saddle Leather, 1969, both published by University of Oklahoma Press.
Access Terms
Frontier and pioneer life -- West (U.S.)
Outlaws -- Bibliography
Criminology -- West (U.S.) -- Bibliography
English language -- Dialects -- West (U.S.) -- Glossaries, vocabularies, etc.
Cowboys -- West (U.S.) -- Language -- Dictionaries
Americanisms -- West (U.S.) -- Dictionaries
Popular culture -- West (U.S.) -- Dictionaries
Correspondence
Manuscripts
Container List
- Series I: Correspondence, 1946-1969
  - Correspondence: Miscellaneous. 1947-1969 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence: Robert McCubbin. 1964-1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Gary Leland Roberts. 1962-1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Texas Institute of Letters. 1964-1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: University of Oklahoma Press. 1964-1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Westerners Groups. 1946, 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: William Wittliff (Encino Press). 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Manfred Wolfenstine. 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Carl W. Breihan. 1954-1969 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Angus Cameron (Alfred Knopf). 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Paul W. Galleher (Arthur H. Clark Co.). 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Paul Arthur Lundgren. 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Joseph G. Rosa. 1964-1969 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Series II: Manuscripts, 1941-1969
  - Western Words: A Dictionary of the American West, 1941-1968
    - Western Words: Correspondence. 1941-1962 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Western Words: Revised edition, typescript, p. 1-199. 1968 (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
    - Western Words: Revised edition, typescript, p. 200-918. 1968 (Box 2, Folder 1-7)
  - Six-Guns and Saddle Leather, 1969
    - Six-Guns and Saddle Leather: Revised edition, typescript, preliminary material and p. 1-824. 1969 (Box 3, Folder 1-5)
    - Six-Guns and Saddle Leather: Revised edition, typescript, p. 825-1529, index p. 1-220. 1969 (Box 4, Folder 1-6)